前情提要
唐宁街里仍未有任何消息传出
There's still no word from inside Downing Street. . .
但是更多政要接二连三走进首相府
Though we are getting even more new arrivals.
我们是斯利辛
We are the Slitheen.
我们把地球先熔成渣 再卖掉
Reduce the Earth to molten slag, then sell it.
离开这颗行星 否则我会阻止你们
Leave this planet or I'll stop you.
世界交给你了
The world is in your hands.
六个月后
数据我检查过了 我反复检查了好几遍
I've checked the figures, I've checked them again and again.
结果都一样
Always the same result.
这样设计隐患很大 可能害死数百万人的
The design is not safe. It could result in the death of millions.
我求您了 趁一切为时未晚 停掉项目吧
I beg of you, stop the project right now before it's too late.
唉 真是
Well... Goodness me.
克里夫先生 您果然是专家
Obviously, Mr Cleaver, you're the expert.
那您会停掉项目吗
Then you'll stop it?
看来我别无选择了
It seems I have no choice.
原谅我失态了
Oh... Do excuse me.
公职太忙 我饭都没吃好
Civic duties leave little time for a sandwich.
您保证您会马上停掉项目吧
But you promise you'll stop it today?
当然了
Well, of course.
没什么比人命更重要了
Nothing is more important than human life.
您把我看成什么人了 疯子吗
What do you take me for, some sort of maniac?
当然不是
Why, no.
您的计算结果 只有我一个人看到吧
Am I right in thinking you've shown your results only to me?
就您一人 别人都不知道
Just to you, no-one else.
这就对了
Wise move.
我跟您说 市长女士
I can tell you, Mrs. Mayor,
这事让我心里压力非常大
this is such a weight off my mind.
我几乎睡不着觉 我自己也不相信读数结果
I've barely slept. I couldn't believe my own readings.
后果之严重
The scale of it...
英伦三岛就从未见识过如此规模的破坏
Destruction like the British Isles has never seen before.
如果我不知情的话
If I didn't know better,
我简直要认为是有人有意让项目出问题了
I'd almost think that someone wanted this project to go wrong,
就好像他们就是想抹掉整座城市似的
as though they intended this city should be wiped off the map.
谢天谢地 我们有您的英明领导
Thank goodness we've got you, our esteemed leader.
神秘博士第一季第十一集
炸弹城
卡迪夫中央火车站
出站口
你是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
什么我是谁啊
What do you mean, who the hell am I?
你又是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
杰克·哈克尼斯上校
Captain Jack Harkness.
不管你卖什么 我们不买
Whatever you're selling, we are not buying.
一边去
Get out of my way!
这应该就是米奇了吧
Don't tell me, this must be Mickey.
大麻烦来了
Here comes trouble!
路上顺利吧 小里奇 -是米奇
How are you doing, Ricky boy? - It's Mickey!
别理他 他逗你玩呢
Don't listen to him, he's winding you up.
你真美
You look fantastic.
真甜蜜 瞧瞧这一对
Aw, sweet! Look at these two.
怎么就没人抱我呢
How come I never get any of that?
先请我喝一杯
Buy me a drink first.
你太难伺候 -但你绝不后悔
You're such hard work. - But worth it!
你找到了吗
Did you manage to find it?
给你 -我现在哪都能去了
There you go. - I can go anywhere now!
我说过了 你用不着护照
I told you, you don't need a passport.
在审判星球和水晶金字塔上
It's all very well going to Platform One
或一号平台也许用不着
in Justicia and the Glass Pyramid,
可万一要去巴西呢 我可能需要的
but what if we end up in Brazil? I might need it.
要知道 我什么都准备着
You see, I'm prepared for anything.
听这意思你要长住了
It sounds like you're staying, then.
你们在卡迪夫干什么
So what are you doing in Cardiff?
那边那位弹簧杰克男又是谁
And who the hell's Jumping Jack Flash?
我不介意你跟招风耳呆在一起
I don't mind you hanging out with Big Ears there. . .
怎么说话呢 -自己照镜子去
Oi! - Look in the mirror.
但这家伙 我说不准 他有点
But this guy, I don't know, he's kinda. . .
英俊吗 -倒不如说油头粉面
Handsome? - More like cheesy.
在21世纪俗语里油头粉面是好话还是坏话
Early 21st-century slang, is cheesy good or bad?
坏的
It's bad.
但是坏意思是好的 对吧
But bad means good, isn't that right?
你是说我就不英俊吗
Are you saying I'm not handsome?
我们就是停一下补充燃料而已
We just stopped off, we need to refuel.
卡迪夫地下有一条裂谷横穿城市
The thing is, Cardiff's got a rift through the middle of the city.
虽然看不见 但就像地震裂缝一样
It's invisble, but it's like an earthquake fault
这是不同维度之间的裂缝
between different dimensions.
这裂缝1869年就闭合了
The rift was healed back in 1869.
多谢一个叫格温妮丝的女孩
Thanks to a girl named Gwyneth.
因为有种叫做格尔斯的怪物
Cause these creatures called the Gelth,
试图从裂缝中穿越到这里
they were using the rift as a gateway,
但她拯救了世界 关闭了裂缝
but she saved the world and closed it.
但尽管裂缝关闭了 一些小口子还是有的
But closing a rift leaves a scar,
这些口子会产生的能量对人类无害
and that scar generates energy, harmless to the human race...
但正是塔迪斯需要的 所以我们停几天
But perfect for the Tardis. So just park here for a coupl of days,
就停在这个裂口上 然后
right on top of the scar. And...
打开引擎 尽情吸收能量辐射
Open up the engines, soak up the radiation. . .
就像给她加满油一样就能上路啦
Like filling her up with petrol, and off we go!
遨游时间 -和空间
Into time! - And space!
天呐 瞧瞧你们个的样子
My God, have you seen yourselves?
你们觉得自己挺聪明 是不是 -是啊
You all think you're so clever, don't you? - Yep.
没错 -对头
Yeah! - Yup.
还需再充24小时 所以我们有点空闲时间
It should take another 24 hours, so we've got time to kill.
那个老太太在盯着我们看
That old lady's staring.
可能在琢磨四个人挤在木头小警亭里做什么
Probably wondering what four people can do inside a small wooden box.
你到底是哪的上校 毒舌小队的吗
What are you captain of - the Innuendo Squad?
慢着 不能丢下塔迪斯不管吧
Wait, the Tardis, can't just leave it,
不会被发现吗
doesn't it get noticed?
是啊 这警亭外观是怎么回事
Yeah, what's with the police box?
为什么是这个样子 -这是一种伪装设备
Why does it look like that? - It's a cloaking device.
名字是辟易线圈
It's called a chameleon circuit.
塔迪斯无论降落在哪里 都会作相应的伪装
The Tardis is meant to disguise itself wherever it lands.
比如说如果降落在古罗马
Like if this was ancient Rome,
她就会伪装成雕像基座之类的
it wiil be a statue on a plinth or somthing.
但我降落在了1960年代 她伪装成警亭
But I landed in the 1960s, it disguised itself as a police box,
然后线圈就卡住了
and the circuit got stuck.
她是参考已有的东西 真有这样的警亭
So it copied a real thing, there actually was police boxes?
是啊 就在街角
Yeah, on street corners.
在无线电和手机出现前 就用这个报警求助
Phone for help, Before they had radios and mobiles.
如果他们逮捕了什么人
If they arrested somebody,
他们就可以把人塞进这里等待增援
they could shove 'em inside till help came.
就跟小型监房似的
Like a little prison cell.
那你为什么不修修线圈呢
Why don't you just fix the circuit?
我喜欢 你不喜欢吗 -我好喜欢啊
I like it, don't you? - I love it.
我说的就是这个意思
But that's what I meant,
现在没有警亭了 难道不会引起注意吗
there's no police boxes any more, so doesn't it get noticed?
里奇 我就跟你解释解释人类行为吧
Ricky, let me tell you something about human race,
你把一个神秘蓝箱子公然扔在闹市中心
you put a mysterious blue box slap bang in the middle of town,
人们会怎么做 根本不管直接走开
what do people do? Walk past it.
别说废话了 咱们去逛逛去
Now stop your nagging, let's go and explore.
有什么计划吗 -我不知道
What's the plan? - I don't know.
这是21世纪初的卡迪夫
Cardiff, early 21st century,
而且今天刮的是 东风
and the wind's coming from the... East.
相信我吧 这是全宇宙最安全的地方了
Trust me. The safest place in the universe.
这座位于卡迪夫市中心的核电站
This nuclear power station right
将会为社会各阶层带来更多工作岗位
in the heart of Cardiff city will bring jobs for all!
如各位所见 身为市长
As you can see, as Lord Mayor,
我不得不批准一些激进的改建工程
I've had to sanction some radical redevelopments.
不要拍照 我刚怎么说的来着
No photographs! What did I say?
请您随意拍摄这项目 但不要拍我 谢谢
Take pictures of the project by all means, but not me, thank you.
那么
So. . .
卡迪夫城堡将被拆除
Cardiff Castle will be demolished,
为高大光荣的布莱德鲁格项目腾地方
allowing the Blaidd Drwg Project to rise up, tall and proud,
这将是威尔士工业的一座纪念碑
a monument to Welsh industry.
你们难免有人会对此心存质疑
And, yes, some of you might shiver.
"核电站"这个词
The words "nuclear power station"
和"人口中心"这个词
and "major population centre"
放到一起并不是那么和谐
aren't exactly the happiest of bedfellows.
但我以个人名誉保证
But I give you my personal guarantee
只要我活在这世上一天
that as long as I walk upon this Earth,
就决不会有市民因此受伤害
no harm will come to any of my citizens.
现在请举杯庆祝吧
Now drink up, a toast. . .
敬未来 -敬未来
To the future! - The future!
相信我
And believe me. . .
这项目会璀璨夺目的
it will glow.
打扰了布莱恩女士 我是卡茜·索特
Excuse me, Mrs Blaine, my name's Cathy Salt,
我是《卡迪夫公报》记者
I represent the Cardiff Gazette.
抱歉我不接受采访 我向来不自我宣传的
I'm sorry, I'm not doing interviews. I can't bear self-publicity.
但您听说过诅咒吗
But are you aware of the curse?
你什么意思 卡茜是吧
Whatever do you mean? Cathy, wasn't it?
卡茜·索特
Cathy Salt,
您的一些工程师是这么想的
that's what some of your engineers are saying
布莱德鲁格项目被诅咒了
that the Blaidd Drwg Project is cursed.
我听着挺傻的
Sounds rather silly to me.
我也是这么想的 我只是报道些乡土新闻
That's what I thought, I was just chasing a bit of local colour,
但有趣就有趣在你把这些事联系起来看
but the funny thing is when you start peacing it all together
确实会让人觉得有点怪
it does begin to look a bit odd.
怎么说 -那些伤亡案件
In what way? - The deaths.
那些与这个项目有关的死亡事件
The number of deaths associated with this project -
首先就是那整个欧洲安全观察团都死了
First of all, there was the entire team of European safety inspectors.
他们是法国人 这不能怪我
But they were French, it's not my fault,
谁让他们只用威尔士语写"危险易爆"呢
and, "Danger! Explosives!" was only written in Welsh.
然后就是卡迪夫文化遗产委员会的那起事故
And the accident with the Cardiff Heritage Committee.
经调查 那泳池触电事故完全是线路老化
The electrocution of that swimming pool was put down to natural wire entire.
那还有建筑师呢
And then the architect.
当时在下雨 能见度很低 我的车刹不住
It was raining, visibility was low, my car simply couldn't stop.
那最近的政府核能专家克里夫先生呢
And then recently Mr Cleaver, the government's nuclear adviser.
地面结冰滑倒了 -他脑袋都掉了
Slipped on an icy patch. - He was decapitated.
冰面太滑摔得太惨
It was a very icy patch.
我看这些所谓故事
I'm afraid these stories are nothing more
无非就是坊间谣传罢了
than typical small-town thinking.
我实在没时间听这个 请您见谅
I really haven't got time. If you'll excuse me.
不过在他死之前
Except before he died,
克里夫先生把他的发现发了一些在网上
Mr Cleaver posted some of his findings online.
是吗
Did he now?
只要知道怎么找 他非常担心反应堆
If you know where to look. He was concerned about the reactor.
又是那些技术上的事
Oh! All that technical stuff.
尤其是抑压池的设计
Specifically that the design of the suppression pool
会导致氢气复合器无法正常运行
would cause the hydrogen recombiners to fail,
从而引发安全壳隔离系统的急剧崩裂
precipitating in the collapse of the containment isolation system,
进而引发反应堆熔毁
and resulting meltdown.
你调查得还真是周详啊
who's been doing a homework?
那是我的工作
That's my job.
我看 卡茜·索特
I think. . .Cathy Salt. . .
我看你我应该私下里谈谈
I think you and I should have a word in private.
我的胃又不舒服了
Oh, my little tummy's complaining.
我们可能得去趟卫生间了 -我在这等着
We might have to make a detour to the ladies. - I'll wait here.
不像话 咱们女生一起去
Oh, come on! All girls together!
刚才你的那些古怪理论说到哪了
So you were saying? These outlandish theories of yours.
看来我们来得真及时啊
It sounds like we got here just in time.
请继续 -核物理我了解的不多
Continue. - Well, I don't know much about nuclear physics,
但根据我的理解
but from what I could make out,
克里夫认为整个建筑都会炸上天
Cleaver was saying the whole project could go up,
比切尔诺贝利还要惨
worse than Chernobyl.
里面的灯坏了吗
Is there something wrong with the lights?
这破灯总是一闪一闪的
Oh, they're always on the blink.
我都不知道发了多少文件要求修一修了
I can't tell you how many memos I've sent.
接着说 切尔诺贝利
So...Chernobyl?
不仅如此 而且要糟上一千倍
Apparently, but a thousand times worse.
我知道听起来有点假
I mean it sounds absurd,
肯定会有安全措施的
there must be so many safety regulations,
但是听克里夫的意思 这会是核爆浩劫
but Cleaver seemed to be talking about a nuclear holocaust.
他说简直就像有人故意似的
He almost made it sound deliberate.
我们不是《星期日泰晤士报》那种大报
I mean we're hardly The Sunday Times,
我们只是《卡迪夫公报》
we're only the Cardiff Gazette,
但我们还是有义务揭露真相的
but we do have a duty to report the facts.
那你打算刊发这个消息吗
And you're going to print this information?
你还好吗 你听起来… -嗓子疼
Are you all right? You sound a bit... - Sore throat.
有点喉咙痒而已
Just a little tickle.
不过请告诉我 你是不是打算
But tell me, do you intend
将这个消息公之于众 -我不得不如此
to make this information public? - I have to.
那好吧
So be it.
不过告诉你 我男朋友觉得我疯了
Mind you, my boyfriend thinks I'm mad.
我们下个月就要结婚了
We're getting married next month
他说如果我闹出了大事 我会丢了饭碗的
and he says if I cause a fuss I could lose my job,
而我们手头正紧呢
just when we need the money.
男朋友 -杰弗里 公务员
Boyfriend? - Jeffrey, civil servant...
就是个普通人 但也是我的心上人
He's nothing exciting, but he's mine.
婚礼是什么时候
When's the wedding?
19号 其实就是为了堵我妈的嘴
The 19th. It's really just to stop my mother from nagging,
不过我看怀了孕 不结也不行了
but the baby sort of clinched it I suppose.
你怀孕了
You're with child?
三个月了 外形上还看不出来
Three months. It's not showing yet.
怀上孩子也是个意外
It wasn't planned, it was an accident.
不过是个甜蜜的意外
Nice accident, though.
恭喜你 -谢谢您
Congratulations. - Thank you.
你呢 你有孩子吗
How about you? You got any kids?
没有
No.
你结婚了吗
Is there a Mr Blaine?
离了
Not any more.
现在我自力更生了
I'm all on my own.
不过我曾有一个大家庭
I had quite a sizeable family once upon a time.
兄弟们可爱极了
Wonderful brothers...
个个胆子都大得很
Oh, they were bold!
但他们都不在了
But all of them gone now.
也许你说得对 也许我是遭了诅咒了
Maybe you're right. Maybe I'm cursed.
我才不这么想 怎么会呢
Oh, no, I don't think so, not really.
你真是太好了
You're very kind.
抱歉 我还得再待一会儿
If you don't mind, I might be a while.
你先走吧 也许改天我们接着谈
You run along. Perhaps we could do this another day.
您还好吗 -好得很
Are you all right? - Fine!
不如这样吧
OK, I tell you what,
我把详细资料放在您办公室里
I'll leave my details with your office.
多谢您和我说话
Thanks for talking.
也谢谢你
Thank you.
你就满嘴扯谎吧
You're lying through your teeth!
原来那白色的东西是大尖牙
I mean, it turns out the white things are tusks,
大尖牙啊 它醒过来 非常不高兴
and I mean, tusks! And it's woken and it's not happy!
你怎么就没发现它在那 -我们15个人
How could you not know it was there? - 15 of us,
一丝不挂 然后我就说 "不是我干的"
naked, and I'm going like, "Nothing to do with me!"
然后它吼叫起来 我们就赶紧跑
Then it roars, and we are running!
死了命地跑啊
Oh my God, we are running!
布拉科维奇摔倒了 然后我转身对他说
Brakovitch falls, so I turn to him, and I say...
我就说我们该左拐吧 -我就是这么说的
I knew we should've turned left! - That's my line!
你说的话我一个字都不信 太扯了
I don't believe a word you say! That is so brilliant!
你们的衣服拿回来了吗
Did you ever get your clothes back?
没有 我一把他扶起来就往船上跑
No, I just picked him up and went right for the ship,
全速疯跑 一直开着船冲进了太空
full throttle. Didn't stop while I hit the space.
我全身那个抖啊
I mean I was shaking!
太不可思议了 我吓死了都
It was unbelievable! It freaked me out...
等我停下飞船 已经到了15光年开外了
Now and by the time I got there I was fifteen lightyears away.
然后我就想 当初为什么要来呢
Then I realized, why this?
我就没一天安宁
And I was having such a nice day.
《西部邮报》
新市长 新卡迪夫
据情报
According to intelligence,
目标是斯利辛家族最后一个幸存者
the target is the last surviving member of the Slitheen family,
来自拉克西科里科弗拉帕多里斯星的犯罪家族
a criminal sect from the planet Raxacoricofallapatorious,
假扮成人类
masquerading as a human being.
披着一张人皮
Zipped inside a skin suit.
进攻计划 我们执行57-56号基础战略
OK! Plan of attack, we assume a basic 57-56 strategy,
封锁一楼所有进出口
covering all available exits on the ground floor.
博士 你和她正面对抗 守住1号门
Doctor, you go face to face, that'll designate exit 1.
我守2号门 洛斯3号 米奇4号
I'll cover exit 2. Rose, exit 3. Mickey Smith, exit 4.
听明白了没
Have you got that?
不好意思 该谁发号施令
Excuse me. Who's in charge?
抱歉 等候指示 长官
Sorry. Awaiting orders, sir.
好 计划如下
Right, here's the plan.
就听他的 好计划
Like he said. Nice plan!
还有补充吗 -举枪致敬吧
Anything else? - Present arms.
准备好了 -准备好了
Ready. - Ready.
设置快速拨号 -好了
Speed dial? - Yep.
完成 -就绪
Ready. - Check.
地狱见吧
See you in hell.
你好 我来见市长大人
Hello, I've come to see the Lord Mayor.
您有预约吗
Have you got an appointment?
不 就是个老朋友顺道看看 给她个惊喜
No, just an old friend, passing by, bit of a surprise.
真想看看她什么表情 -她正在用茶
I can't wait to see her face. - She's just having a cup of tea.
你只管进去告诉她 博士来看她了
Just go in there and tell her the Doctor would like to see her.
哪位博士 -就是博士
Doctor who? - Just the Doctor.
原话告诉她 博士来了
Tell her exactly that, the Doctor.
请您稍等
Hang on a tick.
市长说她很感谢您突然来访
The Lord Mayor says thank you for popping by.
她也很想和您叙叙旧
She'd love to have a chat but,
但是 她实在是忙不过来了
em... She's up to her eyes in paperwork.
您可以预约下周再来吗
Perhaps if you could make an appointment for next week?
她正在爬窗逃走 是不是 -没错
She's climbing out of the window, isn't she? - Yes, she is.
斯利辛朝北逃窜了
Slitheen heading north!
这就去 -收到 完毕
On my way. - Over and out.
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
别伤害市长
Leave the Mayor alone!
玛格丽特
Margaret!
4号出口是谁把守
Who's on exit 4?
是米奇 -我来了
That was Mickey! - Here I am!
大傻子米奇
Mickey the idiot.
别怪他 她总不能跑得比我们快吧
Oh, be fair, she's not exactly gonna outrun us, is she?
她有传送器 这是作弊
She's got a teleport, that's cheating!
这下我们别想抓她了
Now we're never gonna get her!
博士玩传送器玩得可溜了
Oh, the Doctor's very good at teleports.
我可以陪你玩一整天
I could do this all day.
你们这是公然迫害
This is persecution!
干嘛总追着我不放 我怎么惹着你了
Why can't you leave me alone? What did I ever do to you?
你想杀我
You tried to kill me
还打算毁掉整个地球
and destroy this entire planet.
那些先不算
Apart from that?
你是个斯利辛 被困在地球上
So you're a Slitheen, you're on Earth, you're trapped.
你家人全死了 但你传送走了
Your family get killed, but you teleport out.
最后一刻逃了出来
Just in the neck of time.
你却不想逃走 那你打算做什么呢
You have no means of escape, what do you do?
你建了一座核电站 但是目的是什么
You build a nuclear power station, but what for?
我这是做慈善 我已经意识到错了
A philanthropic gesture. I've learnt the error of my ways.
然后你偏偏盖在裂缝上
And it just so happens to be on top of the rift.
什么裂缝 -时空裂缝
What rift would that be? - A rift in space and time.
如果这个核电站熔毁 整个地球都会
If this went into meltdown, the entire planet would...
这个核电站就是设计成
This station is designed
一旦启用立即爆炸的
to explode the minute it reaches capacity.
就没人发现吗 伦敦那边就没人核查这个吗
Didn't anyone notice? Doesn't anyone in London check this stuff?
这里是卡迪夫 伦敦才没人理我们
We're in Cardiff, London doesn't care!
就算整个南威尔士沉进海里他们也不会注意到
South Wales could fall into the sea and they wouldn't notice.
我怎么一股威尔士人腔调
Oh. I sound like a Welshman.
老天 我入乡随俗了
God help me, I've gone native.
她建这个做什么呢
But why would she do that?
那么大的爆炸她自己也活不成
A great big explosion should only end up killing herself.
她有名字 -她都不是个人 是个怪物
She's got a name. - She's not even a she, she's a thing.
但她很聪明
Oh, but she's clever!
妙极了
Fantastic!
这是巨型三相波动力学推进器吗
Is that a tribophysical waveform macro-kinetic extrapolator?
说得非常正确
Couldn't have put it better myself.
天才 这不是你造的吧
Ooh, genius! You didn't build this.
一点小爱好罢了 造些小东西
I have my hobbies. Little tinckering.
不是 我是说这不可能是你造的
No, you really didn't build this.
你的水平还不够 -我猜是她偷来的
Way beyond you. - I bet she stole it.
是我偶然得来的 -这是武器吗
It fell into my hands. - Is it a weapon?
是传送器
It's transport.
如果反应堆爆炸了
You see, if the reactor blows,
裂缝开启 引发了大规模灾难
the rift opens, phenomenal cosmic disaster
但这个东西能把你罩在力场里
but this thing shrouds you in a force field,
就像一个能量防护罩 保你安全
you have this energy bubble, so you're safe.
然后你输入坐标 站在上面
Then you feed it coordinates, stand on top,
乘着冲击波一路飞出太阳系
and ride the concussion all the way out of the solar system.
是个冲浪板 -是全维度冲浪板
It's a surfboard. - A pan-dimensional surfboard.
本来可以成功的
And it would have worked,
我本可以一路飞出这个垃圾星球
I'd have surfed away from this dead-end dump,
回到我的家园
back to civilisation.
你炸掉整个星球就为了搭个车
You'd blow up a planet to get a lift?
就像踩在蚂蚁窝上
Like stepping on an anthill.
这个名字你怎么看 -什么
How did you think of the name? - What?
布莱德鲁格 是威尔士语
Blaidd Drwg? It's Welsh.
我知道 但是你怎么想到的
I know, but how did you think of it?
随手挑的 没什么特别
I chose it at random, that's all.
我也不知道 听着顺耳 有什么关系吗
I dunno, it just sounded good. Does it matter?
布莱德鲁格
Blaidd Drwg.
什么意思 -恶狼
What's it mean? - Bad Wolf.
我听过这个词 恶狼
I've heard that before, "Bad Wolf."
我听见过好几次了
I've heard that lots of times.
我们去哪里 这个词就跟到哪里
Everywhere we go, two words following us.
恶狼 -怎么可能跟着我们呢
Bad Wolf. - How can they be following us?
没什么 巧合而已嘛
Nah, just a coincidence!
就好像听见广播里的一个词
Like hearing a word on the radio,
感觉整天听似的
then hearing it all day.
没什么大不了
Never mind!
还有正事要做
Things to do.
玛格丽特 我们要送你回家
Margaret, we're gonna take you home.
慢着 这不就等于轻易放她走了吗
Hold on, isn't that the easier option like letting her go?
真是难以置信
I don't believe it,
我们真要去拉克西…
we actually get to go to Raxa. . .
等等 是拉克西科里…
Wait a minute! Raxacori...
拉克西科里科弗拉帕多里斯星
Raxacoricofallapatorious.
拉克西科里科 -弗拉帕多里斯星
Raxacorico... - Fallapatorious.
拉克西科里科弗拉帕多里斯星 -对了
Raxacoricofallapatorious! - That's it!
我说对了
I did it!
那里是有死刑的
They have the death penalty.
多年以前斯利辛家族
The family Slitheen was trialed
在缺席情况下被审判有罪
in its absence many years ago and found guilty.
不允许上诉
With no chance of appeal.
根据政府法令
According to the statutes of government,
我一回去就要被处决
the moment I return I am to be executed.
你怎么看 博士
What do you make of that, Doctor?
带我回家 你就带我走向死亡
Take me home, and you take me to my death.
这不是我的问题
Not my problem.
这飞船简直不可思议
This ship is impossible!
非常卓越 你怎么能让它里外差距这么大
It's superb! How do you get the outside around the inside?
你觉得我会告诉你其中奥秘吗
Like I'd give you the secret, yeah.
这下被你打败我心里也平衡多了
I almost feel better about being defeated.
我们之前毫无胜算 这可是神之科技
We never stood a chance, this is the technology of the gods.
别膜拜我 我会是个坏神的
Don't worship me. I'd make a very bad god.
我要是神就不会让你消停的
You wouldn't get a day off for starters.
杰克 大家伙怎么样了
Jack, how are we doing, big fella?
这个外推器是顶级的
This extrapolator's top of the range.
你从哪儿弄到它的
Where did you get it?
我不知道 哪个气闸甩卖上吧
I don't know. Some airlock sale?
肯定是大抢了一场吧
It must have been a great big heist.
它充满能量 -我们能用它补充燃料吗
It's stacked with power. - But we can use it for fuel.
和这船不兼容 但能缩短12小时充能时间
It's not compatible, but it should knock off about 12 hours,
我们早上就能出发了
we'll be ready to go by morning.
那我们晚上就困在这儿了
Then we're stuck here overnight.
我不急
I'm in no hurry.
我们有个囚犯
We've got a prisoner.
这个警察电话亭真成了警察电话亭了
The police box is really a police box.
但你们不仅是警察
You're not just police, though.
既然你们要带我去刑场
Since you're taking me to my death,
这让你们变成了我的行刑人
that makes you my executioners.
你们每个人都是
Each and every one of you.
但你罪有应得
Well, you deserve it.
你话说得轻巧
You're very quick to say so.
你的双手很快就会浸满我的鲜血
You're very quick to soak your hands in my blood.
这样一来 你的罪又能比我轻多少呢
Which makes you better than me how, exactly?
长夜漫漫
Long night ahead.
看看谁能直视我的双眼
Let's see who can look me in the eye.
这外面好冷
It's freezing out here.
也比那里好点
Better than in there.
她罪有应得 她是个斯利辛 我不在乎
She does deserve it, she's a Slitheen, I don't care.
只是在那盒子里感觉怪怪的
It's just...weird in that box.
我其实不需要我的护照
I didn't really need my passport.
我在想 我们可以去喝一杯
I've been thinking, you know, we could...go have a drink,
吃点披萨什么的 就我们俩
have a pizza or something, just you and me.
好主意
That'd be nice.
如果塔迪斯直到早上都走不了 我们可以
And I mean, if the Tardis can't leave until morning we could...
去酒店 共度良宵
Go to a hotel, spend the night?
如果你想 我带了钱 -行啊
I mean if you want to, I've got some money. - OK. Yeah.
真没关系吗 -没事
Is that all right? - Yeah.
好 这附近有几家酒吧
Cool...there's a couple of bars round here,
我们可以去逛逛
we should give 'em a go.
你需要去告诉他一声吗
Do you have to go and tell him?
这和他无关
It's none of his business.
怎么了
So what's on?
没什么 只是
Nothing, just...
我猜你平时不是这样的
I gather it's not always like this.
不得不等待
Having to wait.
我猜你总是最先离开的那个 博士
I bet you're always the first to leave, Doctor.
从不多想后果 只管甩手走人
Never mind the consequences, off you go.
你屠杀我的家人后就跑向宇宙了
You butchered my family and then ran for the stars,
我说的对吗
am I right?
但这次不会了
But not this time.
你终于自食其果了
At last you have consequences.
感觉如何 -我没有屠杀它们
How does it feel? - I didn't butcher them.
别回答 这就是她想要的
Don't answer back, that's what she wants.
我没有
I didn't.
那你呢 你进行了紧急瞬移
What about you? You had an emergency teleport.
你没把它们一起带到安全之处 对吗
You didn't zap them to safety, did you?
它只能带一个
It only carries one.
我得在无坐标情况下飞行
I had to fly without co-ordinates.
我最后降落在犬岛的一个垃圾桶里
I ended up in a skip on the Isle of Dogs.
这一点也不有趣
It wasn't funny.
抱歉
Sorry.
其实挺搞笑的
It is a bit funny.
我可以提最后一个要求吗
Do I get a last request?
要看是什么了
Depends what it is.
我开始有点喜欢人类生活了 这些仪式
I grew quite fond of my little human life, all those rituals.
刷牙
The brushing of the teeth
还有他们烹饪东西的复杂方式
and the complicated way they cook things.
在海湾边有个小餐馆
There's a little restaurant, just round the bay,
是我挺喜欢的一个地方
it became quite a favourite of mine.
这就是你想要的 最后一餐吗
Is that what you want, a last meal?
我难道没有这权利吗
Don't I have rights?
她不会试图逃跑才怪
Oh, like she's not gonna try to escape.
我永远无法从博士手上逃跑
Except I can never escape the Doctor,
有什么危险的呢
so where's the danger?
我在想你能不能做到
I wonder if you could do it.
和一个你要杀掉的生物共进晚餐
To sit with a creature you're about to kill and take supper.
看你吃不吃得下饭
How strong is your stomach?
能做到 -真的吗
Strong enough. - I wonder.
我看过你与敌人战斗
I've seen you fight your enemies.
现在与它们共进晚餐
Now dine with them.
你不会让我改主意的 -证明给我看
You won't change my mind. - Prove it.
外面有人类
There are people out there.
如果你哪怕溜出去一秒
If you slip away just for one second,
他们就会身处险境
they'll be in danger.
不过 我有这东西
Except... I've got these.
你们俩各带一个 如果她离你超过三米
You both wear one. If she moves more than ten feet away, zzzt!
她就会受到一万伏特电击
She gets zapped by 10, 000 volts.
玛格丽特 你想出去吃晚餐吗 我请客
Margaret, would you like to come out to dinner? My treat.
铐在一起吃晚餐
Dinner in bondage.
没问题
It works for me.
我们出来约会
Here we are out on a date,
而你却连我的真名都没问过
and you haven't even asked my proper name.
这不是约会
It's not a date.
你叫什么名字 -布隆
What's your name? - Blon.
我叫布隆·菲富奇·帕萨梅戴·斯利辛
I'm Blon Fel Fotch Passameer-Day Slitheen.
这将是我死亡证明上的名字
That's what it'll say on my death certificate.
很高兴见到你 布隆
Nice to meet you, Blon.
我确信这点
I'm sure.
看 那就是我在当玛格丽特时住的地方
Look, that's where I was living as Margaret,
一个很好的小公寓 那里 在顶上
a nice little flat, over there. On the top.
就在亮灯的那一间旁边
Next to the one with the light on.
两间卧室 海景房 我当时很高兴
Two bedrooms, bay-side view, I was rather content.
我猜我再也见不到它了
I don't suppose I'll see it again.
没错
Suppose not.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
Pleasure!
告诉我 博士
Tell me then, Doctor,
你对我们这个物种了解多少
what do you know of our species?
只有我看到的那些
Only what I've seen.
你知道吗 举例来说 在极端情况下
Did you know, for example, in extreme cases,
当她的生命受到威胁
when her life is in danger,
一个雌性拉克西科里科弗拉帕多里斯星人
a female Raxacoricofallapatorian
可以在她手指内生成一个毒镖
can manufacture a poison dart within her own finger?
我知道 -只是测试一下嘛
Yes, I did. - Just checking.
还有一件事
And one more thing,
是你我之间的小秘密
between you and me...
作为自救的最终手段
As a final resort,
其余的毒素可以从肺部呼出
the excess poison can be exhaled through the lungs.
这样好闻多了 现在点菜吧
That's better. Now then, what d'you think?
牛排看起来不错 牛排薯条
Mmm, steak looks nice. Steak and chips!
前阵子博士带我去了一个星球
The Doctor took me to this planet a while back.
比地球冷多了
It was much colder than this.
他们把这里叫做哭泣的女人
They called it Women Wept.
这个星球被叫做哭泣的女人是因为
The planet was actually called Women Wept coz
如果你俯瞰它 有一片巨大的大陆
if you looked at it from above, there's this huge continent,
好像没什么棱角
like all curved round.
看上去就像个女人 在悲泣
It sort of looked like a woman, lamenting.
天呐 我们去过这么一片海滩
Oh, my God, and we went to this beach, right?
没有人 没有建筑
No people, no buildings,
只有这片绵延千里的海滩
just this beach like a thousand miles across.
有什么事发生了 与太阳有关
Something had happened, something to do with the sun,
我不知道 但是大海一下子就冻上了
I don't know, but the sea had just frozen.
像是在刹那间 在风暴中
Like in a split second, in the middle of a storm, right?
海浪与浮沫都冻了起来 直到海平线
Waves and foam, just frozen, all the way out to the horizon.
在午夜 我们在这些海浪下漫步
Midnight, we walk underneath these waves,
有百尺高 都是冰做的
a hundred feet tall and made of ice.
我在和特丽莎·德莱尼约会
I'm going out with Trisha Delaney.
好吧
Oh, right.
很好
That's nice.
店里的那个特丽莎吗
Trisha from the shop?
对 罗伯·德莱尼的妹妹
Yeah, Rob Delaney's sister.
她人很好
Well, she's nice.
她有点胖 -她减肥了
She's a bit big. - She lost weight.
你一直不在
You've been away.
真为你高兴 她很好
Well, good for you, she's nice.
再和我多说说这星球 -就这么多了
So tell us more about this planet, then. - That was it, really.
公开处刑会采用缓慢的处决方法
Public execution's a slow death.
它们会准备醋酸稀溶液
They prepare a thin acetic acid,
把我放进一个大锅里煮熟
lower me into the cauldron...and boil me.
酸度正好能让皮肤剥离
The acidity is perfectly gauged to strip away the skin.
而内脏则掉入溶液里
Internal organs fall out into the liquid
我就变成汤了
and I become soup.
但依然活着
And still alive.
依然在惨叫 -我不是制定法律的人
Still screaming. - I don't make the law.
但你是执行者
But you deliver it.
你会留下来观刑吗
Will you stay to watch?
不然我还能做什么呢
What else can I do?
斯利辛是个大家族 我们还有很多族人
The Slitheen family's huge, there's a lot more of us,
遍布宇宙各地 带我去找他们
all scattered off-world. Take me to them.
带我去安全的地方
Take me somewhere safe.
但你就会死灰复燃 -我保证不会的
But then you'll just start again. - I promise I won't.
你在那副人皮里呆太久了 已经忘记了
You've been in that skin-suit too long, you've forgotten.
曾经有个真正的玛格丽特·布莱恩
There used to be a real Margaret Blaine.
你杀了她 剥了她的皮用
You killed her and stripped her and used the skin.
你在用一个死去女人的嘴请求宽恕
You're pleading for mercy out of a dead woman's lips.
也许我已经习惯了
Perhaps I have got used to it.
作为人类生活 普通生活
A human life, an ordinary life.
这就想要这么多
That's all I'm asking.
给我个机会 博士
Give me a chance, Doctor.
我可以改 -我不相信你
I can change. - I don't believe you.
你现在想做什么 -不知道
So what do you want to do now? - Don't mind.
我们可以去酒店看看还有没有房间
We could ask about hotels.
那特丽莎·德莱尼怎么办
What would Trisha Delaney say?
说的也是
Suppose.
那边有个酒吧
There's a bar down there
名字好像是西班牙语什么的
with a Spanish name or something...
你根本不喜欢特丽莎·德莱尼
You don't even like Trisha Delaney!
是吗 你知道个屁啊
Oh is that right? What the hell do you know?
可我了解你 我也知道她
I know you! And I know her,
我知道这永远不会发生
and I know that's never gonna happen,
所以你觉得你在骗谁呢
so who do you think you're kidding? !
至少我知道她在哪里
At least I know where she is!
原来如此
There we are, then.
这和特丽莎无关
It's got nothing to do with Trisha,
都是因为我 -你离开了我
this is all about me! - You left me!
我们当时处的很好 很快乐
We were nice, we were happy,
然后你给我一个吻和他跑了
then you give me a kiss and run off with him
你让我觉得自己一文不值
and you make me feel like nothing,
洛斯 我一文不值
Rose! I was nothing!
我不被允许和一个店里的蠢女孩
I can't even go out with a stupid girl
一起约会 因为你一通电话我就得跑过来
from a shop because you pick up the phone and I comes running.
这就是我的用处吗 洛斯 备胎
I mean, is that what I am, Rose - standby?
我是不是该坐在这里等你一辈子
Am I just supposed to sit here for the rest of my life waiting for you?
因为我真的会的 -对不起
Because I will! - I'm sorry.
我向你保证上次见面后我就变了 博士
I promise you I've changed since we last met, Doctor.
就在今天 有个女孩
There was this girl, just today,
一个年轻女孩
a young thing.
危险的是 她快要查出真相了
And something of a danger, she was getting too close.
我感觉嗜血的欲望升腾
I felt the blood lust rising,
就像家族教给我那样
just as the family taught me.
我几乎不假思索就要杀了她 然后
I was going to kill her without a thought. Then...
我停手了
I stopped.
她就活在某个地方 现在
She's alive somewhere, right now,
她在这城市中奔走
she's walking round this city,
因为我可以改变 也改变了
because I can change, I did change.
我知道我无法证明 -我相信你
I know I can't prove it. - I believe you.
那你就知道我可以变得更好
Then you know I'm capable of better.
这不能说明什么
It doesn't mean anything.
我可是留了她一命
I spared her life.
你放一个人走了 但这不是什么新鲜事
You let one of them go, but that's nothing new.
你时不时地放走一个 要么是因为她笑了
Every now and then, a little victim's spared because she smiled,
或是因为他有雀斑 亦或是他们求饶了
cos he's got freckles, cos they begged.
你就是这样让自己心安
And that's how you live with yourself,
就是这样心安理得继续大肆屠杀的
that's how you slaughter millions,
因为有时候 一时兴起
because once in a while, on a whim,
如果哪天心情好 你才会放人一马
if the wind's in the right direction, you happen to be kind.
只有一个杀人犯才知道这点
Only a killer would know that.
对吗
Is that right?
以我看来 你那有趣而无忧无虑的
From what I've seen, your funny little,
人生的尾迹里留下的只有毁灭
happy-go-lucky life leaves devastation in its wake.
总是前进是因为你不敢回头
Always moving on, cos you dare not go back.
玩弄无数人的性命 你可能真像上帝一样
Playing with so many people's lives, you might as well be a god.
而且你是对的 博士
And you're right, Doctor,
你一点都没错
you're absolutely right.
有时 你会放过一个人
Sometimes...you let one go.
放过我吧
Let me go.
我不是让你离开他 因为我知道这不公平
I'm not asking you to leave him, cos I know that's not fair.
但我只是需要点什么 一点保证
But I just need something, some sort of promise,
保证就算你回来也是为了我回来的
that when you do come back, you're coming back for me.
那是打雷吗 -有什么关系呢
Is that thunder? - Does it matter?
那不是打雷
That's not thunder.
在斯利辛家族 我们别无选择
In the family Slitheen, we had no choice.
我在十三岁时被迫第一次杀人
I was made to carry out my first kill at 13.
如果我当时拒绝
If I'd refused,
我父亲就会把我喂给剧毒蛆
my father would have fed me to the venom grubs!
如果我是个杀手
If I'm a killer,
那也是因为我生来就为了杀戮
it's because I was born to kill,
我只知道杀戮
it's all I know!
博士 你到底有没有在听我说
Doctor? Are you even listening to me?
你能听到吗
Can you hear that?
我正在请求宽恕 -听
I'm begging for my life! - Listen, shush.
走吧 你就只管走吧
Ah, go on then, run!
是不是又是他啊 是博士
It's him again, isn't it? ! It's the Doctor!
总是博士
It's always the Doctor!
从来都是博士 而不是我
It's always gonna be the Doctor, it's never me!
我的手铐
My handcuffs!
我觉得你不会想逃跑了
Don't think you're running away.
我跟定你了
Oh, I'm sticking with you!
约个会结果约成了这个样子
Some date this turned out to be!
是裂缝 裂缝正在开启
It's the rift. The rift's opening.
你到底在干嘛 -它失控了
What the hell are you doing? - It just went crazy!
是裂缝 时间空间都在断裂
It's the rift! Time and space are ripping apart,
整个城市都会消失
the whole city's gonna disappear!
是那个推进器 我已经断开连接了
It's the extrapolator! I've disconnected it,
但它依然在给引擎供能
but it's still feeding off the engine.
它在利用塔迪斯 我无法阻止它
It's using the Tardis! I can't stop it!
别想卡迪夫了 它会把整个星球割裂的
Never mind Cardiff, it's gonna rip open the planet.
怎么了 发生什么事了
What is it? ! What's happening? !
我的妙计生效了
Oh, just little me!
敢轻举妄动的话我就把她撕成碎片
One wrong move and she snaps like a promise.
我早该猜到的
I might have known.
我整晚都在听你胡扯
I've had you bleating all night,
可怜虫 现在闭嘴吧
poor baby, now shut it.
你 小飞人 把外推器放到我脚边
You! Fly boy! Put the extrapolator at my feet!
多谢
Thank you.
就像我计划的一样
Just as I planned.
我以为你得炸掉核电站才行
I thought you needed to blow up the nuclear power station.
如果失败 要是有人来抓我
Failing that, if I were to be...arrested,
那么任何有能力追踪我的人
then anyone capable of tracking me down
自己就拥有相当先进的科技
would have considerable technology of their own.
所以 他们就会被推进器吸引过来
Therefore...they would be captivated by the extrapolator.
尤其是像你这样爱四处收集的人 博士
Especially a magpie mind like yours, Doctor.
所以外推器被设定成执行B计划
So the extrapolator was programmed to go to Plan B -
锁定最近的异星能量源开启裂缝
to lock on to the nearest alien power source and open the rift.
而它找到了如此巨大的能量源
And what a power source it found...
我的计划又可以启动了
I'm back on schedule...
多谢你了
thanks to you.
裂缝将会震荡
The rift's gonna convulse,
你会毁了这星球 -而你们会为它陪葬
you'll destroy the planet. - And you with it!
而我将乘着这块飞板
While I ride this board
越过炼狱之顶飞向自由
over the crest of the inferno all the way to freedom!
退后 小子们
Stand back, boys!
我要走了
Surf's up!
开启裂缝意味着你会把这飞船扯成两半
Of course, opening the rift means you'll pull this ship apart.
那又怎样
So sue me!
这不像是老式的能量源
It's not just any old power source.
这是塔迪斯 我的塔迪斯
It's the Tardis, my Tardis.
全宇宙最好的飞船
The best ship in the universe.
它会碎成美丽的碎片的
It'll make wonderful scrap.
那道光是什么 -是塔迪斯之心
What's that light? ! - The heart of the Tardis.
这飞船是有生命的 你打开了它的灵魂
This ship's alive. You've opened its soul.
它
It's...
如此明亮
so bright...
看着它 玛格丽特
Look at it, Margaret.
真美
Beautiful...
看看里面 布隆·菲富奇
Look inside, Blon Fel Fotch.
看着这光
Look at the light.
谢谢
Thank you.
别看 站着别动 闭上眼
Don't look! Stay there, close your eyes!
杰克 快来把它关上
Jack, come on, shut it, shut it all down!
洛斯 去那边的控制板
Rose, that panel over there,
把所有开关扳到右侧
turn all the switches to the right!
干得漂亮 谢谢你们
Nicely done. Thank you, all.
玛格丽特怎么了
What happened to Margaret?
应该是被烧光了 自我执行了死刑
Must've got burnt up, carried out her own death sentence.
不过我觉得她没死
No, I don't think she's dead.
那她会去哪里
Then where'd she go?
她看到了塔迪斯之心
She looked into the heart of the Tardis.
即便是我也不知道效力有多强
Even I don't know how strong that is.
而飞船会心灵感应
And the ship's telepathic,
像我告诉你的那样 洛斯
like I told you, Rose,
它会进入你的脑海 翻译异星语言
it gets inside your head, translates alien languages.
也许纯能量可以翻译所有的思想
Maybe the raw energy can translate all sorts of thoughts.
她在这儿
Here she is!
她变成一只蛋了吗
She's an egg?
退化到童年时代了 -她成了一只蛋
Regressed to her childhood. - She's an egg!
她可以重新开始新生活
She can start again. Live a life from scratch.
如果我们带她回家
If we take her home,
把她交给一个能好好抚养她的家庭
give her to a different family who bring her up properly,
她可能可以正常成长 -也可能更坏
she might be all right. - Or she might be worse.
这是她的选择
That's her choice.
她变成了一只蛋 -一只蛋
She's an egg. - She's an egg.
天呐 米奇
Oh, my God, Mickey!
我们充能完毕 可以离开了
We are all powered up. We can leave.
裂缝的开启让飞船充满了能量
Opening the rift filled us up with energy,
我们可以出发了 如果没问题的话
we can go. If that's all right.
好的
Yeah, fine.
米奇还好吗 -他没事 他走了
How's Mickey? - He's ok. He's gone.
你想去找他吗 我们可以等
Do you wanna go and find him? We'll wait.
不用
No need.
他该找更疼他的人
He deserves better.
我们出发吧 不停前行
Off we go, then. Always moving on.
下一站 拉克西科里科弗拉帕多里斯星
Next stop, Raxacoricofallapatorious.
这词可没多少机会说
Now you don't often get to say that.
我们就路过把她放进孵化场里
We'll just stop by and pop her in the hatchery.
斯利辛人玛格丽特可以重新开始生活
Margaret the Slitheen can live her life again.
第二次机会
A second chance.
那真是太好了
That'd be nice.
告诉你件事 你现在是房客了
I gotta tell you something, you're a housemate,
下集预告
你进入房子了
you're in the house!
这是不是很棒
Isn't that brilliant?
欢迎来到《智者为王》
Welcome to The Weakest Link.
我们要给你一个全新形象
We're giving you a brand-new image.
我穿的有什么不对吗
What's wrong with what I'm wearing?
怎么回事 -她被驱逐了
What was that? - She's been evicted.
这可不光是个游戏 -我需要找到博士
This isn't just a game. - I need to find the Doctor!
他就在这里的哪个地方 他一直都在
He's gonna be here somewhere! He's always here!
有什么其他事情发生了
There's something else going on.
有选手在游戏之外
We have contestants outside the games.
它们惧怕博士 -告诉我 它们是谁
They fear the Doctor. - Tell me, who are they?
这不可能
That's impossible.
我认识这些飞船 它们被销毁了
I know those ships, they were destroyed.
显然它们活了下来
Obviously they survived.
警报 警报 我们被发现了
Alert, alert! We are detected!